Pranava Swaroopa

+1 864-908-5756 | pswaroo@clemson.edu | linkedin.com/in/pranavaswaroopa | github.com/ppswaroopa | Clemson, SC

Summary

Graduate student at Clemson University's automotive engineering program at CUICAR specializing in Vehicle Autonomy. Two years of work experience as an engineering consultant and one year as a research assistant. Professional & research experience in Python, C, C++, and MATLAB. Have hands-on experience in developing and implementing deep learning algorithms.

EDUCATION

Clemson University International Center for Automotive Research

Greenville, SC

Masters of Science in Automotive Engineering, Specializing in Vehicle Autonomy (3.7/4.0)

2021 - Present

Manipal Institute of Technology

Manipal, India

Bachelors of Technology in Mechanical Engineering

2013 - 2017

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Intern

January 2023 – Present

Adam Hoover(PI), Dept. of Electrical & Computer Engineering, Clemson University

Clemson, SC

- Using Computer vision collect and generate data-set for off-road autonomy.
- Building optimal neural network models by testing in the field.
- Deployed ROS with Jackal for data collection and testing.

Graduate Research Assistant

September 2021 – December 2022

ARMLAB, Clemson University - International Center for Automotive Research

Greenville, SC

- Evaluating simulation fidelity of skid-steer robots with Project Chrono, CoppeliaSim(V-Rep), and Gazebo.
- Developing reinforcement learning algorithms in the context of skid-steer robots like Husky.
- Using ROS-MATLAB tool-chain in building autonomous mobile robots.

Research Assistant

July 2020 – June 2021

Agrawal Lab - Centre for Molecular Neurosciences, Kasturba Medical College

Manipal, India

- Collaborated with Drosophila neuroscientists and developed 3D models for behavioral assays that simplify existing environments
- Using 3D rapid prototyping techniques developed tools to increase the productivity of the research.
- Implemented machine learning models and created pipelines for fast and easy video data processing & created a data analysis software in MATLAB.
- Using Raspberry Pi Arduino set up a network storage and processing device for monitoring sensor data.

Assistant Manager

August 2017 - June 2019

Essar Projects India Ltd.

Surat, India

- Generated SOP, Safety and Construction documents for projects as the engineering consultant.
- Successfully collaborated with the teams across disciplines and locations across multiple projects.
- Selected to represent the team with clients in Kuwait.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C/C++, Python

Tools: Git, ROS, MATLAB, Docker, VS Code, Visual Studio, Inkscape

Simulation Environment: Gazebo/Rviz, LG-SVL, CoppeliaSim, Project Chrono

Design Software: SolidWorks, Siemens NX, AutoCAD, CATIA V5, Autodesk Fusion 360

OS: Ubuntu, Windows, Raspberry Pi

Autonomous Navigation using Turtlebot3 | Python, ROS, Raspberry Pi, Git, Ubuntu

Spring 2022

- Lead the team in developing the bot to navigate obstacle courses involving various tasks autonomously.
- Developed PID controllers to use LIDAR data to keep the robot away from all obstacles and be at the center
- Using camera images, developed a PID controller to follow a line on the track and used miniYOLO to analyze and respond to a STOP sign.
- Implemented a cron job to get useful data sent before every test, which resulted in a faster testing schedule.
- For successfully implementing the project, received the highest grade in the class

Drivable Area detection in severe weather using DL | TensorFlow, Python, HPC, Git

Spring 2022

- Selected and processed 15.63K images from the BDD10K dataset.
- Using Convolutional Neural Net(CNN), developed a DNN that detects drivable areas with an mIOU of 44.14%.
- Developed a pipeline that processes a given video and outputs a video with the drivable area overlayed on it.
- Complete project was developed using the Palmetto Cluster, an HPC environment.

Image Segmentation with GUI | C, Win32, Computer Vision

Fall 2023

- Designed a GUI program on Windows using active contour algorithm draws contours.
- Using event handlers, many different options were presented to the user.

End-to-End Deep Learning with Object Detection | LG-SVL, Python, ROS, Docker, Ubuntu

Fall 2021

- Generated an End-to-End deep learning network recorded images from the front camera and steering inputs.
- Using the LGSVL simulation environment, data collection was done by manual driving.
- Resulting network was able to give steering commands by analyzing the front camera images.
- This network was implemented in the Autoware-AI autonomy stack.

Improved object detection using RADAR-Camera sensor fusion | Python, HPC

Spring 2022

- Processed complete nuScenes dataset for Front Camera & Radar data.
- Network was trained with selected data for object detection.
- Performance scores with Camera only data and RADAR data fused were compared.

ADAS implementation on F1-10th car | Arduino, MATLAB

Fall 2021

- Developed PID controllers for Adaptive Cruise Control and Autonomous Lane Keeping
- Both controllers received data from multiple ultrasonic sensors mounted on the F1-10th vehicle.
- These were implemented on an Arduino board for real-time computing requirements.

Model-based systems design | MATLAB, Simulink, AutoCAD

Fall 2021

- Designed a battery electric roadster using MATLAB Simulink models
- Simulink models were generated for Powertrain, Tire Dynamics, and a validating Drive Cycle model.
- These models with a regulation body was visualized to create the roadster.